Nikolaos Liliakidis

Marlow Road, Brighton, East Sussex, BN2 5NB **Mobile:** 07575855085 **Email:** nickliliakides@gmail.com Portfolio: https://nicklils.github.io/nikolaosliliakidis.github.io/

Personal Profile

I'm an ambitious and hardworking person with many years of experience in IT services, Office Administration, as well as running my own business and last 18 months on Web development. I have been interested in programming and computing since I was nine years old and this led me to complete an IT Degree in my home country.

I graduated from the Just IT self-funded training course and my passion for learning new programming languages and technologies in the most rapid growing industry stays imperishable, continuing to gain educational experiences in Open University. I'm seeking to undertake web and software programming tasks and challenges, full responsibly, for personal and career development.

My first priority and challenge is to see myself as a senior IT developer as soon as possible gaining through my employment new skills and knowledge to progress further my career within a challenging environment.

Education and IT Training

07/2017- 01/2018 Just IT Training Ltd, London Development Professional Programme

- MTA Software Development Fundamentals (Expected 2017)
- MTA HTML5 Web Application Development Fundamentals (Expected 2017)
- MCSD Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3 (Expected 2017)
- MCSD Developing ASP.NET MVC Web Application (Expected 2017)

08/2014-Present The Open University, UK

Bachelor Degree - BSc (Honours) Computing and IT, Part Time

Core Modules: Sense Programming, Robotics (Robotlab programming simulator)

Microsoft Networking, Linux, Maths, Web Technologies

Languages: HTML5, C#, Java, Python

08/2011-08/2012 BHMS, Business and Hotel Management School Lucerne Switzerland

Post Graduate Diploma in Hospitality and Business Management

09/2001-06/2003 National Institute of Professional Training and Education Thessaloniki, Greece

Certified Degree in "Applications Technician on ITs and Networks"

Core Modules: MS Office (Word, Excel, Access), Pascal, Visual-Basic, C++, Unix, SQL,

Networking Essentials, Maths, Computer Hardware Essentials

IT Skills

Software Development Skills: JavaScript, React, Redux, Git, ASP.Net, SQL,

Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS, SaSS, Bootstrap, MaterialUI

Core Programming Languages: JavaScript, C#, Python, Java

Operating Systems: Microsoft Windows, Mac OS X, Linux, Android

Projects:

My best projects are presented on my portfolio website "https://nicklils.github.io/nikolaosliliakidis.github.io/" in Projects section where the visitors can see all details and information from implementation and user interaction with all of them till links to read the code in Github.

Employment History

12/2018-Now

R3ality Projects, Brighton, UK http://www.realityprojects.co.uk Front-end developer (contract)

- Developing a gas company client management application.
- Core libraries and frameworks used: React, Redux, MaterialUI.
- Basic React template Fuse2 and source control via git and sourcetree.
- Other libraries used: axios, moxios, lodash, react-dropzone, react-table etc.
- Test driven development with Jest and Enzyme.

08/2017-Now

Hermes Web Development, London - Brighton, UK https://hermeswebdev.co.uk Founder/Developer/Designer/Technician

- Creating web pages and applications using HTML, CSS-SaSS, JavaScript-React-Node, ASP.Net.
- Seeking and finding suitable domain and hosting services for our clients.
- Supporting, upgrading and maintaining our creations.
- Providing consulting and technical support to our clients.
- Computer sales, repairs and refurbishments.

03/2018-04/2018

Farmco International, Watford, UK Web Developer (8 weeks placement)

- ASP.Net Core Unit Testing.
- Testing and debugging code of Company's leading upcoming projects.

09/2015-08/2017

The Real Greek, Spitalfields Market, London, UK Restaurant Supervisor/Assistant Manager

- Dealing with stock, orders and invoices, inputting data into the company's database system.
- Organizing and cooperating with front and back of the house to run busy shifts smoothly.
- Dealing with 'difficult' customers and complaints and solving problems that can occur.
- Banking and closing daily shifts, reporting and sending numbers and stats to the head office and operations.

11/2012-09/2015

Park Plaza Sherlock Holmes Hotel, Baker Street, London, UK Food and Beverage department - Head waiter/Supervisor/Trainer

- Working at the front of the house of Bar, Restaurant, M & E, Room service and Minibar.
- Organizing and maintaining and refilling minibars. Testing and replacing broken sensors.
- Supporting Front Office technically when needed, training F&B newcomers.

06/2010-08/2011

Junknet Internet Station, Kalamaria, Thessaloniki, Greece Front Office Administrator, Assistant Manager

- Logging clients into the network and managing the server application.
- Organising, developing business webpage and working on the front desk.
- Sorting out technical problems and issues on software and hardware devices.

02/2004-09/2010

Digital DVD movies, videogames, Internet Cafe and IT services Thessaloniki, Greece Owner, General Manager

- Selling and renting movies, videogames and data media.
- Providing a Local Area Network for customers and groups to surf the web and play onine games.
- Providing technical support on software and hardware of computers and mobile devices.
- Developing company's website.

09/2003-01/2004

BiSoft Net software development, Perea, Thessaloniki, Greece Sales Department

- Seeking, finding and contacting potential customers (Property Agents and Dentists).
- Booking appointments with the clients and arranging presentation of the applications.
- Debensains also annilications to End machines and bensa and measure to the board desirations.

Interests and Achievements

Computing: Since I was 9 years old I was writing programs on Basic and playing games on my AMSTRAD CPC 6128 or my friend's Spectrum, Commodore 64 and a bit later Atari ST and Amiga game consoles back to 80s and 90s. Since early on 21th century I use Internet and computers in a more advanced level and I also studied and became software, hardware and network technician. I use very efficient plenty of Operating systems, application and services like: Microsoft Windows, Mac OS, Linux, Microsoft Office, Visual Studio, Adobe Photoshop, Ableton, Sound Forge, Social Media, Remote connection services and many more. Except technologies and Web I have a big passion for music, cinema, sports and quality food.

References available upon request